A very warm welcome to the ICICI Lombard
General Insurance Company Limited Q2 and
H1 FI 2026 earnings conference call from
the senior management we have with us
today Mr. Sanjie Mantri MD and CEO of
the company Mr. Gopal Balachandran CFO
Mr. Anan Singhi Chief Retail and
Government Mr. Girishnaek, Chief
Technology and Health Underwriting and
Claims. Mr. Sep Goradia, Chief Corporate
Solutions International and Bank
assurance. And Mr. Goro Vora, Chief
Reinsurance, Underwriting and Claims for
Property and Casualty.
Please note that any statements comments
are made in today's call that may look
like forward-looking statements are
based on information presently available
to the management and do not constitute
an indication of any future performance
as future involve risks and
uncertaintities which could cause
results to defer materially from the
current views being expressed. As a
reminder, all participant lines will be
in the listenon mode and there will be
an opportunity for you to ask questions
after the presentation concludes. Should
you need
assistance during the conference call,
please signal an operator by pressing
star and then zero on your touchstone
phone. Please note that this conference
is being recorded. I now hand the
conference over to Mr. Sanjie Mantri, MD
and CEO ICICI Lumbar General Insurance
Limited. Thank you and over to you sir.
>> Thank you. Good evening to each one of
you. Thank you for joining the earnings
conference call of ICSL OMARD for
quarter 2 and H1 financial year 2026.
I would like to commence with a brief
overview of the recent economic and
industry trends which have shaped the
operating environment over the past few
months. Following that, our CFO Mr.
Gopal Walachandan will take you through
the company's financial performance for
the first half ended September 30th.
During the quarter ended June 2025, the
Indian economy sustained its robust
growth trajectory, registering a GDP
growth of 7.8% marking a 5-year quarter
high and surpassing expectations despite
global uncertaintities.
The sovereign credit rating upgrade by
S&P Global coming after 18 years
reflects enhanced confidence and India's
economic fundamentals, fiscal prudence
and related policies.
Following on the heels of the 100 basis
repo cut and targeted income tax
incentives, the government has now
unveiled a landmark over of the GST
framework which is expected to
turbocharge consumer sentiment
by rationalizing rates and simplifying
compliance. The reforms are expected to
make essential goods and services more
accessible and affordable.
This is expected to unlock stronger
broad-based private consumption and
accelerate economic activity.
Collectively, these three policies
actions are projected to inject nearly
2,200 to 3,100 billion into the economy.
More importantly, these pathbreaking
reforms are expected to provide a
significant boost to the non-life
insurance sector.
The exemption of GST from individual
health insurance premium will make
healthcare protection more affordable
for households and is expected to
increase the lives covered.
In addition, the rationalization of GST
rates in the automoil sector has lowered
the overall cost of vehicle ownership.
We truly believe that this will increase
private mobility enabling more Indians
to own vehicles and encouraging upgrades
to premium models.
In line with our customer first
philosophy, we are committed to passing
the complete benefit of lower GST rates
to our policy holders.
In conjunction with the above reforms, I
would like to update on the quarter to
2026 numbers and well on the trends
observed along with their impact to the
general insurance industry.
The health segment continues to remain
the largest contributor to the industry
and accounts for almost 40% of GDPI mix
in H1 of 2026.
While the market continues to be
moderated due to the 1 byN accounting
norm post September 2025, we have
witnessed a significant uptick in the
retail inensity segment of the business.
We remain confident that more
individuals and families will continue
to enter the health insurance fold and
expand their coverage.
Now coming to the auto sector in quarter
2 2026 this is the data published by
Fada auto industry has grown by 1.3%.
The private car segment grew by 2.9 and
the two-heer segment has seen a modest
growth of.5%.
However, for the month of September
2025, private car sales grew at 5.8%
and two wheelers at 6.5% compared to
September 2024.
Notably and more importantly for the
first 9 days of Navaratri period the
private car and two wheelers growth
stood at 34.9 and 36% respectively when
compared to the Navatri period for 2025
which is a significantly positive even
after adjusting to pent-up demand. These
trends coupled with our dominant
presence in the OEM space give us
confidence for a positive momentum in
the second half of the year.
While the global economic environment
remains volatile and uncertain, India's
strong macroeconomic fundamentals
supported by pro-conumption policy
stance. We are expected to which are
expected to act as a buffer and continue
to drive domestic economic momentum.
Given the supportive regulatory
environment, we expect general insurance
industry to sustain it growth trajectory
over medium to long term.
Now coming to the industry performance
for the period ended September 30, 2025.
The general insurance industry reported
a GDPI growth of 7.3% for the period
excluding crop and health segment. The
GDPI growth stood at 10.5%.
For the referred period H1 2026,
speaking of specific segments within the
industry, the commercial segment
reported a growth of 14.2% 2% for the
period ending H1 2026. The growth was
majorly driven by the fire line of
business which witnessed a robust
increase of 20.5%
during the refer period and the same
contributes to more than 50% of the
commercial business. The motor segment
growth for the industry stood at 7.6%
for the period H1 2026.
This segment continues to face
significant pricing pressure as
reflected by higher industry combined
ratio for motor line of business.
However, as also spoken already, the
current with the current momentum, we
expect H2 of 2026 to reflect improved
growth levels with the first half of the
financial year.
The health segment including mass health
grew by 7.8% for the period ending H1
2026. Within this the group of business
grew at 8.9% for H1 2026 whereas the
retail health growth stood at 9.3% for
H1 2026 impacted by the one by end
accounting norm. Speaking on the
underwriting performance of the industry
overall the combined ratio for the
industry deteriorated from 1 month 3.9%
in quarter 1 financial year 2025 to 115%
in quarter 1 2026.
The overall combined ratio for private
players remained flat at 110.8%
for the period quarter 1 2025 with
110.7% for quarter 1 2026.
Combined ratio for the motor line of
business continues to remain elevated at
125% for quarter 1 2026.
Our continued emphasis on profitable
growth delivered a lower combined ratio
of 102.9% in quarter 1 2026 over 12
percentage point better than the
industry average. I will now proceed to
present a company's performance across
three business segments for the period
H1 2026.
The company reported a degrowth of.5% in
GDPI compared to the industry growth of
7.3% for the period H1 2026.
However, excluding the crop and mass
health segment, the company recorded a
growth of 3.5%
while the industry grew at 10.5% for the
period H1 2026.
In the commercial line segment, our
growth stood at 6.5% for H1 2026 as
compared to the industry growth of 14.2%
for the period H1 2026.
We continue to drive profitable growth
through prudent underwriting, judicious
risk reduction and through our multi-
channelannel distribution. While growth
in the fire segment in quarter 1 2026
stood at 10.3%.
We have been able to steadily increase
growth in quarter 2 2026 to 27.3%.
Specifically in the month of September
2025 we grew at 36.4 in fire segment.
We retained our leadership portion in
engineering liability and marine cargo
line of business for the period ended H1
2026.
Furthermore, we continue to play the
role of a risk solution partner to our
corporate customers through while
providing them best-in-class value added
services which helps them mitigate risk
with holistic management solutions.
In the motor segment, our growth stood
at 2.2% for H1 2026 as against the
industry growth of 7.6%
for the period H1 2026. While I grow
while our growth in the first 5 months
of the financial year stood at 1.3%. The
month of September 2025 witnessed a
sharp uptick due to the festive demand
and moderation of vehicle price
attributable to the GST rate cutting a
motor influence growth to 6.5%.
In an increasingly competitive market
environment witnessed over the recent
quarters, we expect to maintain the
growth momentum that kicked off in
September while remaining focused on a
journey of profitable growth.
underpinned by continuous distribution
expansion and gradual portfolio
segmentation.
Importantly, we continue to maintain our
leadership position in this segment with
a market share of 10.4% in H1 of 2026.
We remain agile and are constantly
taking conscious calls to optimize the
portfolio profitability and a result of
these efforts a portfolio mix for
private car two-wheer and commercial
vehicles which stood at 52.9%
25.3% and 21.8% respectively for H1 2025
has moved to a mix of 54.3%
25.8% 8% and 19.9% respectively in H1 of
2026.
In health segment, we grew by 4.2% for
H1 2026 as again the industry growth of
7.8% for the period
on a 1 byN basis. Our retail business
demonstrated strong growth of 25.2% 2%
for H1 2026
significantly outpacing the industry
growth of 9.3% as of H1 2026.
Consequently, a market share is improved
from 3.2% in H1 2025 to 3.7%
as of H1 2025. For the month of
September 2025, company has crossed 4%
market share in retail health and this
has happened for the first time. This
performance has been driven by an
ongoing product innovation and sustained
investment in strengthening our retail
health distribution capabilities.
This segment is expected to see an
upward trajectory due to the GST
reforms.
The growth the group health segment
recorded a degrowth of 6% for H1 2026
over H1 2025 with a market share being
at 8.7% as on H1 2026.
The observed degrowth is attributable to
a decline in business generated from the
health benefit portfolio on account of
muted disbbursements in the unsecure and
micro finance sectors. However, on the
overall group health portfolio, we
continue to maintain a disciplined
approach and in the month of September
in particular, we have grown at 10.5% as
compared to industry degrowth of one of
1.8%.
I would also like to apprise you of
certain strategic initiatives that
continue to drive operational excellence
and customer centricity across the
organization.
A I have has further strengthened on
ground claim support for our health
customers. In H1 of 2026, the initiative
touched over 58,000 customers, up from
34,000 in the same period last year. We
received feedback from over 20 22,000
customers in H1 of 2026. 94.4% 4% rated
their experience as exemplary which has
given us 4.5 as a rating over five
highlighting the support during claims
processing and assistance within with
hospital coordination.
This reaffirms our focus on
best-in-class service to our customers
during the moment of truth that and that
is all that matters. Our retail health
claim settlement ratio within 30 days
stood at 99.6% 6% for H1 2026, placing
us among the industry top performers and
underscoring our commitment to prompt
efficient claim servicing.
The company launched differentiated
service debts in June 2025. These desks
provide tailor servicing for two
priority customer segments, senior
citizens and high product density
customers. By identifying these profiles
at the point of contact and routing them
to specialized customer relationship
managers, we ensure conversations are
empathetic, personalized, and
valuedriven. Over 96,000 calls were
handled between June to September under
this initiative, generating there in 300
3,000 cross-ell opportunities. Our
belief is that differentiated care
simultantly builds loyalty and long-term
value. Our
take care app a one-stop solution for
insurance and wellness need has now
crossed 18.4 million downloads
reflecting growing customer engagements
and digital adoption. The gross return
premium earned from the take care app
during the period H1 2026 was 2088.2
million with the premium earning of H1
2025 which stood at 8 million.
We have continuously enhanced our
efficiency levels in motor claims. Our
preferred partner network services 75.1%
of our nonoem claims for quarter 2 2026
up from 72.8% in quarter 2 2025.
Furthermore, in the motor insurance own
damage segment, 96.4% of our total
claims were paid within 30 days for H1
2026.
If we look at the industry numbers for
the period quarter 1 2026, the same
stood at 82.4%.
Clearly highlighting IC Lumbar superior
claim settlement practice.
Our unwavering focus on putting the
customer for first continues to reflect
in our net promoter score for quarter 1
2026.
We recorded an NPS of 72 for health
claims and 66 for motor claims.
Demonstrating strong satisfaction level
and reinforcing our position as a
customercentric organization.
We continue to demonstrate strong
resilience in face of rapid evolving
industry dynamics underscoring our
unwavering focus on delivering
sustainable and long-term profitability.
Our strategic direction is firmly rooted
in a oneeye one team philosophy which
promotes collaboration, operational
excellence and a unified approach across
the organization. In conclusion, GST and
other regulatory reforms being positive
for the general insurance sector, we are
well positioned to ride this momentum,
responsibly scaling our reach,
sharpening our value proposition and
converting a more supportive demand
environment into sustained highquality
performance.
I will request Gopar to take through the
financial numbers for the recently
concluded quarter and half year. Uh
thanks Sanjie and uh good evening to
each one of you. I will now give you a
brief overview of the financial
performance of the recently concluded
quarter and half year. We have uploaded
the results presentation on our website.
You can access it as we walk you through
the performance numbers. Uh with effect
from October 1, 2024, long-term products
are accounted on a 1 byN basis as
mandated by the regulator IID. Hence, H1
FI 2026 or for the matter of fact even
quarter 2 2026 FI numbers are not
comparable with the prior periods. uh
please refer to our investor
presentation for further details. The
gross return premium of the company was
at rupes 151.11 billion in H1 FI26 as
against rupees 148.79 billion in H1 FI25
a growth of 1.6%.
GDP of the company was at rupes 143.31
billion in H1 FI26 as against rupes
144.09 billion in H1 FI25 a degrowth
of.5%
against the industry growth of 7.3%.
Excluding crop and mass health, GDPI
growth of the company was at 3.5% as
against industic growth of 10.5% in H1
FI26.
GDP of the company was at rupees 65.96
billion in Q2 FI26 as against rupees
67.21
billion in Q2 FI25 a degrowth of 1.9%
against the industry growth of 5.9% for
the same period excluding crop and mass
health GDPI growth of the company was at
3.5%.
As against the industry growth of 9.8%
in quarter 2 FI26,
our GDPI during the quarter was mainly
driven by growth in the preferred lines
of business. The overall GDPI of our
commercial line segment grew by 6.1% to
rupes 15.84 billion in Q2 FI26 as
against rupes 14.93 billion in Q2 FI25.
On the retail side of the business, GDP
of the motor segment was at rupes 25.11
billion in Q2 FI26 as against rupes
24.82 82 billion in Q2 FI25 registering
a growth of 1.2%.
The advanced premium numbers was rupes
39.13 billion as at September 30 2025 as
against rupes 38.07 billion as at June
30 2025. GDP of the health segment was
at rupes 16.49 billion in Q2 FI26 as
against rupes 15.29 billion in Q2 FI25
registering a growth of 7.8%. Our agents
including the point of sale distribution
count was 1 lakh 47,408
as on September 30, 2025 up from 143 675
as at June 30 2025. During the quarter
the industry witnessed multiple CAT
events mainly floods in various parts of
the country thereby impacting our
combined ratio which was 104% for H1
FI26 as against 103.2% 2% for H1 FI25
excluding the impact of CAT losses of
rupees 73 billion in H1 FI26
and rupees 94 billion in H1 FI25.
The combined ratio was 103.3%
and 102.2% respectively.
Combined ratio was 105.1%
in Q2 FI26 as against 104.5%
in Q2 FI25
excluding the impact of CAT losses of
rupees 73 billion in Q2 FI26 and 94
billion rupees in Q2 FI25.
The combined ratio was 103.8%
and 102.6% respectively. Our investment
assets during the quarter rose to rupes
562 billion as at September 30 to 2025
up from rupes 554.53 billion as at June
30, 2025. Our investment leverage net of
borrowings was 3.57 times as again
September 30, 2025 as against 3.74 times
as at June 30, 2025. Investment income
was at rupes 25.38 billion in H1 FI26 as
against rupees 22.52 billion in H1 FI25
on a quarterly basis investment income
was at rupes 12.49 billion in Q2 FI26 as
against rupes 11.24 billion in Q2 FI25
average capital gains net of impairment
on investment assets stood at rupees
6.16 billion in H1 FI26 as compared to
rups 5.21 21 billion in H125.
Capital gains net of impairment on
investment assets stood at rupees 2.36
billion in Q2 FI26 as compared to almost
a similar number of rupees 2.37 billion
in Q2 FI25.
Our profit before tax grew by 22.3% and
stood at rupees 20.71 billion in H1 FI26
as against rupes 16.93 billion in H1
FI25. Whereas profit before tax grew by
17.2% 2% at rupees 10.77 billion in Q2
FI26 as against rupes 9.19 billion in Q2
FI25. Consequently, profit after tax
grew by 22.9%
and stood at rupees 15.67 billion in H1
FI26 as against rupees 12.74 billion in
H1 FI25. PAD grew by 18.1% at rupes 8.2
2 billion in quarter 2 FI26 up from
rupees 6.94 billion in Q2 FI25.
Return on average equity was 20.8% in H1
FI26 as against 20.3% in H1 FI25. The
return on average equity for the quarter
2 FI26 was 21.4%.
As against 21.8% in Q2 FI25.
Solveny ratio was at 2.73 times as at
September 30, 2025 as against 2.7 times
as at June 30, 2025
continued to be higher than the minimum
regulatory requirement of 1.59 1.5
times. Solveny ratio was at 2.69 as at
March 31, 2025. The board of directors
of the company has declared an interim
dividend of rupes 6.5 per share for H1
FI26 as against rupees 5.5 per share for
H1 FI25.
As I conclude, I would like to reaffirm
that we continue to stay focused on
driving profitable growth and
sustainable value creation while
protecting the interest of our
stakeholders and customers at all times.
We'll be happy to take any questions
that you have. Thank you.
>> Thank you very much. We will now begin
with the question and answer session.
Anyone who wishes to ask a question may
press star and then one on their
touchstone phone. If you wish to remove
yourself from the question queue, you
may press star and two. Participants are
requested to use handsets while asking a
question.
Ladies and gentlemen, we will wait for a
moment while the question queue
assembles.
Our
first question comes from the line of
pre Jane from Motila Losal. Please go
ahead.
>> Yeah. Hi everyone. Congrats on a decent
set good set of numbers. Uh firstly you
know uh just on this GST uh impact right
uh the input tax credit will not be
available for the health insurance
piece. uh and so what was the impact of
that in uh whatever the sales would have
happened in uh 2Q and uh secondly you
know how uh going ahead how are you kind
of uh trying to offset this whether
through commission cards or uh balancing
it uh across the product um product uh
other products that you have that would
be my first question
>> so uh pre I think um um u September it's
just about 9 days so and therefore to
that extent I think is honestly too
premature to kind of call out in terms
of uh what uh has been the impact. I
think the key thing to look out is what
we kind of spelt out as a part of the
opening script. I think what we are
seeing on ground I think the demand
momentum seems to be very very promising
and to that extent is what we have kind
of clearly uh got reflected as a part of
uh clearly increased volume of uh retail
health policies getting sourced. Uh I
think the key to look for is how do we
see let's say things playing out uh over
the next couple of quarters. We are very
very optimistic in terms of how this
particular reforms is likely to kind of
play out and in that context is how we
have kind of looked at even let's say
possibly the uh uh eventual impact of
any input tax credit on uh sourcing. I
think obviously to that extent I think
we have kind of I think which is which
is there I think we have clearly
communicated that uh it will be a part
of the overall distribution cost in
terms of how do we kind of manage the uh
cost of sourcing. So in that context is
what even any related input trade it
will be part and parcel of that that's
the way how we are looking at it but
more importantly as I said I think what
we are quite excited and uh and
optimistic is the relative uh scale up
that one expects consequent to this uh
reforms that has got announced
>> yeah I absolutely I think uh just to uh
put across uh we've been always
discussing debating in terms of what the
sweet spot can be can it be 12% can it
be this Eventually this stimulus which
has come has been the biggest marketing
in terms of letting the customers of
every Indian know that how important
health insurance is and this move is
very significant in terms of managing a
cost structure uh something uh which any
which way there was always a need I
think the industry is working to make it
much more reasonable and it's also a
win-win because the volumes that will
come on account of that will also see
that our partners have enhanced you know
income which will come. So there is a
clear play which is evident and uh for
us as a multi-line company more so uh it
puts us in a very uh comfortable spot uh
because we've got other lines also. This
is one component of the whole thing and
we are seeing tremendous uh tailwinds.
You can see our own growth numbers on
retail genity uh which have been way
ahead of the industry and this further
stimulus that comes in also gives us an
ability to scale at a much faster speed
with a responsible underwriting. So the
guardrail which will continue to guide
us is that we underwrite in a
responsible manner and then the rest
should uh flow out and get evened out
with the with the volumes that will come
through it.
>> Sure. uh but just further on that you
know uh Gopal or any any impact that you
would have seen in due to I understand
it's just for 9 days uh but you know
there would that have elevated the cost
ratios in this quarter uh in 2Q for the
health segment and also uh you know are
you looking to increase the distributor
uh are you looking to cut the
distributor commissions any
communications or any negotiations that
would have been started on the in in
that regard.
So one I think as we keep saying uh uh
pre I think uh when you look at the
sourcing uh objective particularly in
the context of retail health we have
always kind of looked at in the context
of the combined ratio of the book that
we are kind of wanting to write at and
there I think clearly if you see even uh
uh on the on the loss experiences pretty
much uh even if you look at quarter two
or even for the matter of fact half year
I think the loss experience have pretty
much played out in line with our uh
expectations. So hence to that extent I
think the portfolio is kind of doing
well and linked to that is your cost of
sourcing which is obviously a part and
parcel of the overall combined numbers
which is what I called out at this point
of time the way we are looking at is uh
I think whatever cost that we would
incur as a part of uh of sourcing we'll
pretty much factor in also the related
possible loss that one is expected to
see consequent to any loss of input
trade that we will see in the context of
retail health but having said that I
what what is more relevant is what even
Sanji was kind of articulating. I think
we will be kind of pretty much kind of
pleased to look at how things will play
out for quarter 3 and this is something
that even the distributors will start
kind of uh seeing the impact and the
benefits. uh the increased volumes
automatically translates into a better
revenue stream for them and therefore
when they look at their overall u
distribution income uh they would kind
of clearly realize that they are clearly
far better off in terms of where they
are and at this point of time no
significant changes to let's say
whatever our overall uh cost of sourcing
has been I think anything that we would
incur as a part of sourcing would also
include the elements of input tax
dissolvance possibly that we will see on
the retail book.
Got that. Uh Google, the other question
was if I look at the uh NWP to GWP uh
that ratio is uh uh has inched up uh uh
any change in reinsurance strategy which
has kind of moved that or it's just a
product mix kind of a uh change.
>> You have the answer P and so therefore
to that extent is what we keep saying. I
think uh our businesses is obviously
kind of cyclical on different lines of
businesses. Uh as you would have seen uh
in quarter 2 last year, I think we did
have a relatively higher proportion of
uh crop mix uh which obviously has a
relatively lower retention compared to
that. If you'd have seen quarter two of
this year, I think our proportion of
crop is definitely much lower and hence
to that extent and therefore to that
extent and and the fact that retail
health for us has kind of done very
well. Uh I mean it was Q2 of last year
is when we had kind of largely launched
elevate as a solution and through the
next 12 months as we speak is where we
have been able to kind of witness an
improvement in uh sourcing and which is
what we spoke about also market share in
the month of September exceeding more
than 4%. uh so given the fact that also
kind of done well where predominantly we
kind of end up retaining a large part of
the risk on the net. So hence short
answer no change to the thought process
in terms of uh reinsurance philosophy
more the outcome on the net premium to
gross premium is purely a function of
the change in the business mix that one
has seen between quarters.
>> Perfect. Last question.
>> Sorry to interrupt sir. May we request
your return to the question queue for
follow-up questions.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. Uh ladies and gentlemen, in
order to ensure that the management is
able to address questions from all the
participants in the conference, please
limit your questions to only two per
participant. If you have any follow-up
questions, you may rejoin the queue. I
our next question comes from the line of
Madukar Lada from Nama Wealth
Management. Please go ahead.
>> Uh hi. Uh so couple of questions from my
side. uh first uh if I look at the
commission ratio that's uh in stock uh
significantly in uh Q2. So uh uh
probably more uh you know product mix
and is it also because of uh longerterm
products that we're writing? Uh is it
because of that? Uh second
uh on motor OD we see an inch up in the
loss ratio
uh and uh you know very high comparative
intensity and we're losing sort of
market share uh also in in that line of
business.
So um with with the GST cut uh what
would you expect from here? Do we should
we expect sort of the comparative
intensity to come down and uh some
market share recovery happening over
there and why are our loss ratios going
up despite we being sort of more
conservative in this line of business?
So Badukar I think on the first part I
think again as we keep saying one is
what you rightly answered and what I
kind of talked about I think there is
always an element of change in uh change
in the business mix in terms of what you
look at uh in quarter 2 versus let's say
quarter 1 or even for the matter of fact
when you look at even visually a
comparable quarter uh but the larger the
larger way that we have always looked at
is in the context of the overall expense
of management which as a company as we
keep saying is something that we are
very very conscious of and even if
whether you look at it for uh on a half
yearly basis I think our uh our
expensive management numbers are well
within the limits of the 30% threshold
that uh one has put out. uh so hence in
that context I think we are pretty much
on course in terms of what we want to do
and again at the end of the day
commission ratios again whichever way
you look at it will also be a function
of what mix of business do you end up
doing more in terms of new uh renewal
and in the context of retail health that
we spoke about I think that's kind of
doing well uh in terms of the overall
loss experience a large part of the book
that we have sourced also in comes in
the context of as a a new growth and
that would entail some amount of uh cost
of sourcing. So, so a lot of factors but
if you ask us I think what we are quite
comfortable with is the fact that I
spoke about in the context of making
sure that we stay within the guarded
rail of uh within the 30% limit on
overall existence of management uh to
your second
>> is there any impact uh sorry is there
any impact of GST uh ITC in order
>> which is what I called out I think at at
least so far as quarter two is concerned
which is why I kind of also responded to
pri's question I think uh at this point
of time honestly uh the commission
ratios does not have any factor uh uh
any significant impact at least in so
far as uh the impact of GST is
concerned. uh to the second point on the
motor uh own damage loss ratios. I think
this is something that I keep talking
every quarter um for I think we should
keep looking at one is of course is is
quarter toquarter a right comparison
honestly as we keep saying there are
various factors or nuances that go into
uh the loss ratio numbers and uh
secondly as I as we have always
mentioned in the past I think the better
way to look at is more in terms of motor
as a category and that to more on
ideally on a year-to- date basis and if
you and if you recollect just to refresh
the overall Motor loss ratio range that
we have spoken about to the streets have
been in the range of 65 to 67%. And even
if you look at the first half numbers
for overall motor I think the overall
loss ratio stands that if I remember the
numbers correctly it's about 66.6%.
So it's well within that range of 65 to
67% in terms of what we want to operate
and hence but yes between periods there
can always be let's say some bit of uh
volatility to the overall loss numbers
but honestly I think what we are again
comfortable with is within the range
that one is operating at
>> and also Maduka just to add to this for
you and everybody else who are you know
on the call is also the configuration of
business if you see uh relatively if the
new business is on the higher side the
loss ratios do tend to get lower while
the old one o the loss ratios are high
so there's a mix that comes in and uh
you know that the growth if you leave
aside what happened you know prior to
September 22nd uh was very muted so we
were seeing lot more growth coming from
the old veer where loss loss ratio can
be a bit more elevated so there there's
element also which gets played out uh uh
we and there is also quarter to little
bit of cash part that comes on to play
which makes the loss ratios look
elevated. So there's a combination which
has got us. We don't see any challenge.
We continue to maintain our discipline
and we are excited about the fact that
uh the industry may only see record
numbers in the coming quarter.
>> Yeah. Okay.
>> And uh just on the comparative interrupt
may we request you return to the queue
for follow-up questions please as there
are several other participants waiting
for their turn.
Thank you.
Our next question comes from the line of
Sankit Koda from Aenders Park. Please go
ahead.
>> Uh yeah. Uh thank you for the
opportunity. Uh uh Gopal given given GST
cut IDB will come down. So it is fair to
assume that um your your motor odi loss
ratios invariably will go up because of
the vehicle GST cuts and and do you
think the ro depletion which could
happen because of the higher loss ratios
in motor OD can it be more than
compensated or at least compensated by
the extra float either in the form of
advanced premium or or the premium
you'll collect because of the new sales
will be good enough to to to to see the
uh positive rough on the profitability
and and related that on on TP side uh
given given uh GST on CV has been
reduced and and uh and and you have
input credit benefit so in indirectly it
is kind of a price hike to you guys so
so just wondering that given we were
never that's such a strong player in CV
segment uh given given we are seeing a
bit of uptick in CV segment in second
quarter compared to 1Q whether whether
you'll change a bit of strategy on CV
going ahead or not so so that's that's
largely the question I have on motorbs
Yeah, I think possibly Sankit you have
actually answered what you wanted to
ask. So therefore to that extent I think
pretty much uh pretty much uh pretty
much what you kind of asked. I think uh
one um I think on the motor home own
damage side again let's look at it in
the context of what's happening on
ground. I think there seems to be
clearly a lot of cheer that clearly is
an element of pent-up demand and
therefore pretty much similar to what I
spoke in the context of health. I think
what we are again uh then this is there
in terms of the data that was released
by far which is what we kind of also put
out as a part of the opening transcript
clearly there seems to be a renewed
momentum on ground in terms of uh in
terms of increased uh volume of vehicle
sales and that's an area from an ISIS
alone standpoint where we clearly have
an edge and that's the reason why we are
specifically also called out to see say
that relative to what one had
experienced in the first 5 months when
you look at particularly for the month
of September I think we have been able
to kind of get back a lot of our uh uh
lost momentum and hence to that extent I
think we believe we are positively
placed in so far as the opportunity for
the future is concerned on the impact on
uh the possible deduction of course as
we have again articulated as a
responsible uh institution we will
obviously make sure that whatever is
required to be passed on to the
consumers in the form of uh the reforms
that has been entailed pretty much on
course to make sure that all of those
things will be completely passed on and
that's what we have
And uh and of course uh as you rightly
said there are those various factors
depending on what volumes or what type
of vehicles our customers wanting to buy
will be a factor to determine how some
part of the impact will get played out.
Our own efficiencies that we can bring
about in the context of the business mix
that we write will also be an element
that will kind of to some extent take
care of some of the possible impact that
one would uh see on the book assuming we
don't do uh anything on uh on on the uh
on the uh drop in the value of the
vehicle and three is obviously again a
function of the claim efficiencies. I
think as an organization again we have
been speak we have time and again spoken
about the various claim intervention
initiatives that we have kind of worked
on all of this as which is why we called
out even at the time when this
announcements were made we had said that
all said and done I think from an ICIS
alarm standpoint I think we should be
able to kind of take some of this impact
within the overall uh scale of
operations. Uh I think the key thing to
look out for will be how does things
play out over the next couple of
quarters. Uh which is where we are kind
of very very positive and optimistic in
terms of how do we see things playing
out on ground. On the impact side I
think we think this is something that we
should be able to kind of manage within
within the overall scale of operations.
Got it. Got it. Gopal and and lastly on
data keeping this reinsurance accepted
business 462 crores what we did in sec
current quarter or even a much bigger
number in first half it is largely
related to which line of business uh and
this number will continue even in second
half.
>> So again shank this question just does
keep coming uh to us uh on different uh
at different time points. I think as
what we have clearly maintained is
pretty much similar to what we have kind
of talked about in the context of uh
crop. I think uh these are opportunistic
uh these are opportunistic uh calls that
we take purely from an underwriting
standpoint. Uh whatever fits within our
underwriting acceptances criteria is
what we end up writing whether it is for
direct or even for the matter of fact as
reinsurancees acceptances. But each of
this even if you look at it on a full
year basis for example last year our
overall proportion of reinsurance
acceptances to the total volume of gross
premiums that we would have underwritten
as a company has been clearly a
single-digit number. uh so when you
start looking at some of these numbers
particularly viz with a v a quarter I
think there can always be abrasions when
you look start looking at in the context
of percentages but if you ask us from a
thought process or let's say from a
philosophy standpoints purely guided by
the underwriting filters that we kind of
put in terms of risk acceptance and do
we expect each of these to suddenly
become a very large proportion of our
overall gross premium the short answer
is no it'll be well within the defined
uh limits that we have as an institution
>> got it goas thanks thanks for the
Thanks Ankit.
>> Thank you. Our next question comes from
the line of Nidesh from Invest. Please
go ahead.
>> Uh thanks for the opportunity. My
question is on retail health insurance.
Uh uh so can you share loss ratios in
the retail health insurance and group
health insurance for the quarter and
second is uh what is the share of agency
and non- agency channel in the retail
health insurance? I'm trying to
understand how how we have been able to
show pretty strong growth in retail
health insurance over last one year.
>> Yeah, I was just waiting for this
question to be asked in the context of
the split between uh loss ratios on uh
retail indemnity and let's say the uh
corporate health. U so uh so if you I'll
just first give the numbers for quarter
two last year. Uh and first I will give
the group health or let's say the
employer employee health numbers. uh Q2
last year uh employer employee or group
health numbers was 98% on the loss
ratio. Uh this number for quarter 2 of
the current year stands at about 93.7%.
Uh and on a half yearly basis again
employer employee loss ratio H1 last
year that number was 98%. This number
for H1 of the current year is at 94.6%.
Uh that's employer employee health on
retail indemnity. Again in the same
order quarter two last year the loss
ratio was 70.3%.
And H1 of last year was 71.4%.
And uh if you look at quarter 2 of the
current year the loss ratio on retail
indemnity stands at 65.4%.
And on a half yearly basis it stands at
about 69.7%.
Now just to kind of again refresh on the
retail indemnity book pretty much
similar to what I spoke about on uh
overall motor where to the streets we
have been generally talking about a loss
ratio range that you are comfortable at
65 to 67%. Even on retail health
indemnity the range that we have been
speaking about is to maintain the loss
ratio in the range of 65 to 70 and if
you see on a half yearly basis on the
retail health indemnity book the loss
ratio is within that range of 65 to 70.
So that's where we are in terms of uh
the split of the loss ratio numbers on
the split of uh the business between uh
agency and other than agency generally
the proportion of the book that we do
through agency is about uh 2/3 roughly
and the rest of the book will be of the
balance one/3
growth is
>> and both channels are growing as a
similar pace or
>> agency has been relatively faster at
this point of time uh but it's uh both
of them are in very high zone because
the overall growth itself of the book is
in the 50s range if you look at NBCS so
there are significant traction that we
see and uh we are excited about both the
opportunities whether agency or non-
agency
>> sure sure thank you that's it from my
side
>> thanks
thank you our next question comes from
the line of Ain Singh from MK Global
Please go ahead.
>> Yeah. Hi. Uh good evening. Thanks for
the opportunity. Uh two questions.
First, uh can you please sort of provide
some color on your market share in motor
in terms of new and renewal? Uh I mean
I'm asking because if I understand
correctly, I mean your pricing is uh
reasonably higher than aggressive
competitors and you have a kind of a
strong acceptance at uh the dealer
points. uh so in that context I wanted
to understand if that there's a wide
divergence in market share in the view
of the uh renewable market in motor
that's one second uh now uh with this uh
GST thing uh uh in action uh in terms of
growth driver at the industry level what
do I mean do you think industry uh at
the aggregate level going to uh return
to a strong growth phase probably in the
next year or so because I mean uh in the
recent year motor vehicle sales have
been one kind of a point uh pinpoint
then you also had some of these schemes
fading out of course does not matter for
you much but like crop insurance and all
that have been seeing a bit of a decline
so at the aggregate level what could be
the in terms of value terms premium
driver for the industry probably in
FI27. Thanks.
So uh Ain uh honestly I think what we
can talk about is more at an aggregate
level in terms of motor as a category.
Uh in terms of market share which is
there if you look at the first half of
uh last year we had a market share of
roughly about 10.9% and if you look at
the first half of the current year we
have a market share of roughly about
10.4%. Uh this is both half year to half
year. Uh within that I think uh we keep
kind of toggling between new and
renewal. So honestly I think too
difficult to kind of call out
specifically what could be the market
share because that could keep changing
depending on what kind of a mix of the
portfolio that one wants to kind of
underwrite. So that's the reason why we
don't we not specifically calling out in
terms of what would be a market share
between new and what would be a market
share between uh the renewal book to
your second point on uh do we expect the
demand on ground to sustain even for the
next year. I think honestly we will we
will we will obviously play through the
quarters uh in terms of how how one sees
uh uh demand playing out which is what
we called out even about on the opening
transcript. I think the good part is I
think the the the the the pace of
reforms that has been exhibited across
the various regulatory authorities I
think has clearly set the tone on ground
and that's also kind of reflective in
terms of the outcomes that one has seen
in the initial uh few days of let's say
the quarter ended uh September and the
good news is I think I'm sure all of you
are also equally tracking in terms of
what's happening on ground uh
particularly with respect to the volume
of vehicle sales that's playing out uh
at the initial indications even one was
if one was to see in the months of
October I think the the demand
definitely is kind of uh continuing and
therefore there is a clear expectation
with some of these some of these
actions/reforms that has been exhibited
as I said by the various regulatory
authorities looks to be very very kind
of conducive uh for the momentum to kind
of sustain over the next few quarters
but honestly we will keep coming back to
all of you in terms of what do we see on
ground uh across various quarters but at
least clearly the as what one said uh
the tone that has been set clearly looks
quite promising when you look at the
road ahead understand no no absolutely
right and you know if even if you look
at in a bit of a you know you get to the
second layer of number the total
incremental accretion in motor has been
around 3,300 cr and you see the
distribution of that pie you realize
that you know one PSU itself has picked
up more than 1,000 crores so it's been a
very skewed one where you know things
have moved in a not in a distributed
manner and whenever something like this
is there we'll have to be very very
picky. We still continue to be number
one player as far as motor category is
concerned. We do acknowledge the fact
that a loss of half a percent, it's more
tactical where we do believe if it's not
making sense. We will uh we will let it
pass. Uh but we also are aware that no
one can keep doing something like this
over sustained quarters after quarters.
So we we need to be patient. Uh and just
to add on to the fact uh clearly yes uh
new is a strength that we do see
tremendous uh train tailwind and we
spoke about it very categorically. Will
that lead to motor industry per say
showing a better growth? My the belief
and the answer is clearly we do believe
so but it has to pan out on a more
consistent basis. The only element that
we want to adjust at this point of time
is there was a pent-up demand which also
was there because post August 15 there
wasn't much happening in the market. Uh
our math says even adjust to that
adjusted to that the excitement in the
market uh is very high and uh we will
stay connected. I'm sure those numbers
are which you are all you all are very
well aware of but we see a significant
opportunity in quarter three and
probably even H2 of this financial year
and this should occur well for the
industry uh even for uh next financial
year if that's what your question is
>> thanks any view on motor TP tariffs
>> uh well your guess will be as good as
ours we keep hearing that something is
on the anvil and the industry's demand
per say on seeing uh some bit of a hike
or adjustment or realignment of motor TP
is there in every single forum and we do
expect and believe that we will hear a
positive news on that sooner than later.
>> Thank you. Thank you. Very clear.
>> Thanks Ain.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. Our next question comes from
Sha Shivani from Numura. Please go
ahead.
>> Yeah. Hi. Uh thank you for the
opportunity. Uh I just have one
question. Uh this is on the commercial
segment. Um I mean there have been many
media articles. Uh whether it be fire,
marine, crop, there is increased uh
competitive uh there's increased
competition in the segment. Now I
understand that you guys are still
growing quite well. However, if I look
at your underwriting profit in the fire
book, 1 H over 1, it's down. the
underwriting profit in the miscellaneous
corporate book. Uh I mean it's turned uh
lossmaking in this one versus previous
one. So u uh is it fair to assess that
um uh there has been some uh impact on
our book because of the competition or
the price war that's going on in the
segment in spite of the growth that
we've been delivering. Uh that's just
that's the only question I have.
So, so Sh I think again um I think
particularly on commercial lines uh the
portfolio inherently is subject to an
element of volatility when you look at
it purely from an absolute underwriting
outcome and the reason why we are one is
saying this is uh I think increasingly
you are getting to experience a lot many
more catastrophic events play out or as
a matter of fact even if you possibly
experience any large risk event then to
that extent you may possibly see the
outcome of the underwriting book uh kind
of reflecting an outcome which for a
particular given period could be adverse
compared to any other uh uh relative
reference uh quarters. But having said
that, I think from our standpoint, I
think which is what we have been talking
through consistently. Our approach or
thought process to writing risk has been
to kind of keep looking for
prudent/profitable risk selection uh
portfolio. Uh that's not just across
commercialized even across other lines
of businesses and that's the reason why
I think at an aggregate level in the
initial few months we actually have been
kind of losing again some market. uh but
the good news is again uh things seems
to be kind of looking up quite
positively for us when you see the month
of September and hence to that extent we
continue to stay looking for profitable
uh risk selection uh opportunities
outcomes on underwriting whether you
take fire whether you take miscellaneous
corporate or for the matter of fact
anything from an absolute basis will be
purely reflection of some of the loss
events that could have got played out in
that particular quarter. The real
reflection is I think that's what we
keep saying on the overall commercial
lines book. I think that's a book that
has inherently generated us good uh good
cash flows. Uh it has also enabled us to
kind of generate better roe and overall
the book that we have been writing has
been a decent uh combined ratio outcome.
So that's something from a philosophy
standpoint that we stand committed but
as I said in a given quarter or so from
an absolute outcome will be purely a
function of some of the loss events. So,
so ideally what time period should I
look if I want to understand the fire
performance? So, sh time period I think
summation of quarters which is there the
past 3 years or so if you look at where
the average is can give you a very
decent indication in terms of where the
loss ratio resides uh a quartertoarter
movement as Gopal explained can be very
you know dangerous to take a call. Uh
the long and short what we can put
across very confidently is there was a
cat event there was one or two large
losses which is kind of reflected but it
can play out uh over you know couple of
quarters and you will see a moderation
in the loss ratio overall in time to
come. But the best way to look at it is
dig in the in the past and see in
summation. If you look at last you know
16 you know 10 quarters 12 quarters how
does the loss ratio moves you will get a
very clear indication that this is what
the broadly the range is uh in our mind
uh this is absolutely nothing in fact I
can share with you that the rate which
is there or the risk basis uh we've
realized more than 20% than what we used
to and I would also put across the fact
that this was on a lower base last uh
year if you see the commentary that we
had on fire. Uh the industry was not
pricing it appropriately. Some bit of
semblance has come and that has helped
uh uh each of the industry player
including ourselves. Uh but what we not
what we pride is not on the incremental
risk but the selection of risk that we
want to write and that is what uh can be
a big differentiator over submission of
quarters.
>> Got it. This is very useful. Uh thank
you and all the best.
>> Thanks Sha. Thank you.
>> Thank you. Our next question comes from
the line of Nirj to Nwal from UPS
securities. Please go ahead.
>> Yeah. Uh hi everyone. So I think uh lot
of debate has already happened on this
but still to get more sense on uh how
should one think about you know second
half in terms of growth and combine
both. uh any color will be more helpful
because uh definitely 9 days have been
positive but uh but to get a sense of
you know uh uh because we will be off
base also in terms of 1 by n impact
which started from last 1st October uh
which will also be a uh you know
positive thing uh to support growth. How
should one think about growth and then
obviously in terms of uh underwriting
profits and then overall profits.
>> Thanks. Thanks Nash. Finally uh
hopefully from next quarter onwards we
don't have to really kind of talk about
this n and one by n so therefore to that
extent I think for all of us uh there
will be one set of numbers that we will
kind of uh start looking at it
collectively uh but having said that uh
I think if you look at uh the narrative
that we have largely spoken nearest to
all of you is that uh I think on ground
I think which is what we kind of have
been calling out I think we are very
very excited and pleased with with how
some of the regulatory actions are
getting translated in terms of reforms
on ground and hence to that extent I
think from an IC alumba standpoint I
think we're very very well poised to
capitalize this opportunity of growth
across uh streams of businesses so hence
to that extent I think possibly the
extent of uh market share loss that one
had seen particularly over the last
couple of few quarters I think one
definitely expects that particular trend
line to start getting reversed and hence
to that extent in line with what We have
been saying we should logically start
getting incremental market share vis the
industry uh overall growth numbers
that's more from an overall growth
standpoint but when it comes to more
combined ratios/ roas I think both
Sanjie and all of us I think in general
I think what we have been talking about
is to try and sustain that ro in that
range of 18 to 20%. And even if you look
at it whether you look at quarter two or
even if you look even for the matter of
fact if you look at half year I think we
have largely been able to kind of stay
around the range of 18 to 20% from an
ROE. Uh so and therefore even as we head
into the second half I think we'll be
extremely mindful of making sure that we
able to we are able to sustain this uh
but all of this we will obviously keep a
very very close watch in terms of how
the industry is also kind of declaring
their numbers. So I think we do
understand that some companies have
started declaring results for quarter
two. Uh so and we will see the
directional trend on uh how it plays
out. But from our standpoint I think
that's Sanji if you want to add
anything.
>> No no no I think he's spoken and this is
uh well spoken. I think nothing more to
add to this.
>> Got it. And uh just one bookkeeping.
what is what is the yield uh right now
and the duration of the book and the
long-term portfolio right now versus
last year.
>> So the duration of the book is about
4.74 years and the yield on the book uh
YTM is about 7.39%.
>> And on the long-term portfolio uh if we
have that data handy
>> a long-term portfolio are you referring
in the context of uh on the business
side?
>> Yes. So
the yield
>> so on n to 1 byn I think that's a number
that we have called out separately uh nj
in our investor deck I think if you look
at the total long-term premium that
could have got recognized as premium on
a half yearly basis is roughly about 6.2
billion and for the quarter that number
stands at roughly about 3.6
No. Uh that is helpful. Uh thank you.
>> Thanks. Thank you.
>> Thank you ladies and gentlemen. We will
take this as the last question for
today. I now hand the conference over to
the management uh for closing comments.
No,
>> I think great. I think thank you so much
uh for joining in. Uh we run into uh
festivities uh uh going forward. So we
would wish each one of you and your
family members a great safe happy
Diwali. These are exciting times for us
as an industry.
While there are some questions in terms
of how it will evolve, we truly believe
that uh directionally H2 would see far
more tailwinds. So we will stay
connected. We will uh uh we will look we
look forward to meeting with each one of
you uh as and when you are back with
your respective holidays. have a great
time with your families and uh be safe,
be happy. Thank you so much. Thank you.
Thank you
on behalf of ICICI Lumbar General
Insurance Company Limited. That
concludes this conference. Thank you all
for joining us and you may now
disconnect your lines.